<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Marcin Rogowski</title>
    <link>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mrogowski.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mrogowski.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance Computing</title>
      <link>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/hpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/hpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first became interested in High Performance Computing in 2011 during my M.S. coursework. After a brief Human-Computer Interaction episode, I returned to HPC in 2014 and have worked in this field ever since. Between 2014 and 2019, I worked on Saudi Aramco&amp;rsquo;s reservoir simulator - GigaPOWERS and had the chance to lead the performance optimization efforts. During that time, I had the opportunity to run on several &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.top500.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TOP500&lt;/a&gt;-ranked supercomputers and achieve a few milestones: evaluate the scalability up to 196&#39;608 cores back in 2017, and was involved in record-setting 1-billion-cell simulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of those projects, I gained extensive experience with domain partitioning, matrix-vector multiplication optimization, MPI and OpenMP, fast compression algorithms, MPI tuning and asynchronous I/O.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2020, I started to work on an h/p/r-adaptive framework developed at KAUST&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://cemse.kaust.edu.sa/aanslab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AANSLab&lt;/a&gt; used to simulate turbulent compressible internal and external flows on unstructured grids for industrial applications. I focus on the solver&amp;rsquo;s performance, communication, and scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/hci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/hci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting during my internship at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calit2.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;California Institute for Telecommunications and Information Technology (Calit2)&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ucsd.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of California, San Diego&lt;/a&gt;, I became interested in Human-Computer Interaction. My first project was to use Microsoft Kinect for gesture navigation, head and hand tracking in 3D caves with the application to digital archeology.
Back at KAUST, I continued this project and started working with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://corelabs.kaust.edu.sa/labs/detail/visualization-core-lab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Visualization Core Lab&lt;/a&gt; on the visualization of large biological data sets, interaction, and selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I moved to Saudi Aramco in 2013, I continued research in similar areas. In the Hyper-Dimensional Simulator project, we evaluated different interaction techniques with big data originating from reservoir simulation. In our project with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oblong.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Oblong&lt;/a&gt;, we focused on gesture control. Together, we assessed a range of technologies: Vicon motion capture cameras, Novint Falcon&amp;rsquo;s haptic device, 3D mouse, Leap Motion, Microsoft Kinect, etc. Our product was presented to high local government officials, company representatives as well as the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biometrics</title>
      <link>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/biometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/biometrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2008, as a second-year Computer Science B.Sc. student at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pb.edu.pl/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bialystok University of Technology&lt;/a&gt;, I started working on keystroke dynamics with &lt;a href=&#34;http://biometria.wi.pb.edu.pl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Khalid Saeed&lt;/a&gt;. Keystroke dynamics is one of the biometric methods that can be used to authenticate or identify users. The method falls under behavioral features and is based on how a user performs specific tasks - in this case - how the user types on a keyboard. The typing style was shown to differentiate well between users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea first came as early as 1975 when it was mentioned by R. J. Spillane and has since then been modified and improved on multiple occasions with the results reported as high as 99-100% correct classification. The method can be used for both authentication (strengthening the password or continuously verifying the user&amp;rsquo;s identity) or identification (determining the user based on his typing style).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- In general, in almost all the prior work on keystroke dynamics, the user is asked to type a particular password multiple times. --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work started by analyzing the impact of the database quality on the method&amp;rsquo;s efficiency and continued with the implementation of a JavaScript-based website to collect experimental data. My most significant contributions, however, were in the area of user authentication on mobile devices. Back in 2012, when smartphones started rapidly gaining popularity, I researched authentication methods on mobile devices and proposed keystroke dynamics as one of the solutions. I then implemented a custom Android keyboard that collected extra information from the touchscreen and the gyroscope as users were typing. The resulting ensemble of data from different sensors showed promising results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;smartphone_keystroke_dynamics.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile App Development</title>
      <link>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/mobile_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mrogowski.github.io/project/mobile_app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of my M.S. studies, in 2012-2013, Saad Al-Rawaf (now the founder of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudtoday.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CloudToday&lt;/a&gt;) and I ventured into mobile app development.
One of the more successful attempts was Rethink - a new take on task management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our differentiator was the introduction of trigger-based tasks - reminders that were not activated by date and time but by location, contact with a particular person, or a fact of being connected to a specific WiFi network. While we did not continue the development past 2014, in some terms, our venture was successful. With around 30,000 users, we were featured by major media outlets such as The Washington Post, The Guardian, Stuff, All About Android and others. Similar functionality has since been incorporated in applications such as Apple&amp;rsquo;s Reminders and Google Keep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/rethink-a-reminder-triggered-by-time-or-place/2013/04/13/44bbf77c-a16f-11e2-9c03-6952ff305f35_story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
